Byron Gallery
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Artist/Subject Files, circa 1950s-1991, undated, Series 1:; (Box 1-10, 17; 10.2 linear feet)
  - Trefonides, Steven, 1959-1963 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Trioson, Girodet, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Tumarkin, Igael, 1969-1971 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Turner, J.M.W., undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Twombly, Cy, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Artists "V" Miscellaneous, 1963-1968 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Velardi, Esther, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Venet, Bernar, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Venice Biennale Catalog, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Vilato, undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Viollier, Jean, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Vivancos, Miguel, 1961-1966 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Vlaminck, Maurice, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Vuillard, Edouard, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Artists "W" Miscellaneous, 1961-1970 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Waldman, Paul, undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Warhol, Andy, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Werba, Nadia, 1963-1971 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Wesselman, Tom, undated (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Wilson, Clay, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Wilson, May, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Witkin, Jerome, 1965-1966 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Wunderlich, Paul, 1969-1970 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Wyeth, Andrew, undated (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Artists "X, Y, Z" Miscellaneous, 1965-1970 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Young American Group Shows (1964), 1964 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Youngerman, Jack, 1964-1968 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Youngerman, Jack, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Antonakos, Stephen, Dream Pillow Cases, undated, (Oversized material from Box 1, F9) (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Bayer, Herbert, "Book of Drawings", 1961, (Oversized material from Box 1, F31) (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Goeritz, Mathias, "Retrospective Exhibition: 1943-1963", 1963, (Oversized material from Box 5, F13) (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Klee, Paul, "Sollte Steigen", undated, (Oversized material from Box 6, F4) (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Exhibition Scrapbooks, 1963-1970, Series 2:; (Box 11-14, 17; 4.1 linear feet)
  Fifty-seven exhibition scrapbooks in binder sleeves represent a complete documentary record of Byron Gallery exhibits from 1963-1970. The scrapbook contain a wide variety of materials, including correspondence, catalogs, price lists, installation photographs and slides, printed reproductions of exhibited art work, and newspaper clippings and reviews.
  The scrapbooks are arranged by year, then alphabetically by title of exhibition. Loose and undated material is filed at the end of the series alphabetically.
  - Bayer, Herbert, 1963, (5 folders) (Box 11, Folder 1-5)
  - Nivola: Architectural Projects, 1963, (2 folders; Oversized material housed in Box 17, F5) (Box 11, Folder 6-7)
  - Nivola - Beds and Landscapes, 1963, (5 folders) (Box 11, Folder 8-12)
  - American Landscapes, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - De Sanctis, Fabio and U. Sterpini, 1964-1966, (3 folders) (Box 11, Folder 14-16)
  - Grebenak, Louis, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Kotin, Albert, 1964, (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 18-19)
  - One Hundred Animal Drawings, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Pre-Columbian from Costa Rica, 1964, (3 folders) (Box 11, Folder 21-23)
  - Vivancos, Miguel, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Young Americans, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Box Show [1], 1965, (3 folders) (Box 11, Folder 26-28)
  - Box Show [2], 1965, (4 folders) (Box 12, Folder 1-4)
  - Brown, Judith, 1965-1967, (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 5-7)
  - Guillery and Hogle, Richard, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - McEwen, Rory, 1965-1967, (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 9-11)
  - Paris Review, 1965, (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 12-14)
  - Pre-Columbian Animals, 1965, (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 15-17)
  - Sleigh, Sylvia, 1965, (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 18-20)
  - Talman, Paul, 1965, (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 21-22)
  - Youngerman, Jack, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Yuey, Chinn Yuen, 1965, (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 24-25)
  - Edelheit, Martha, 1966, (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 26-27)
  - Floris, Marcel, 1966, (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 28-29)
  - Friedeberg, Pedro [1], 1966, (6 folders) (Box 13, Folder 1-6)
  - Friedeberg, Pedro [2], undated, (3 folders) (Box 13, Folder 7-9)
  - Group Show, 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Isham, Sheila, 1966, (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 11-12)
  - O'Doherty, Brian, 1966, (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 13-14)
  - Sakier, George, 1966, (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 15-16)
  - Townsend, John, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - 400 Years of Italian Art, 1967, (2 folders; Oversized material housed in Box 17, F6) (Box 13, Folder 18-19)
  - Greek Gold and Modern Sculpture, 1967, (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 20-21)
  - Greeley, Colin, 1967, (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 22-23)
  - Grilo, Sarah, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Krebs, Rockne, 1967, (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 25-26)
  - Spyropoulos, Jannis, 1967, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 27-28)
  - Hirst, Barry, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - McDowell, Barrie, 1968, (3 folders) (Box 13, Folder 30-32)
  - Meadmore, Clement, 1968, (4 folders) (Box 13, Folder 33-36)
  - Saff, Donald, 1968, (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 37-38)
  - Small, Neal, 1968, (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 39-40)
  - Sonenberg, Jack, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Friedeberg, Pedro, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
  - Milllington-Drake, 1969, (2 folders; Oversized material housed in Box 17, F7) (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
  - Benson, Ben, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Matta, 1970, (5 folders) (Box 14, Folder 6-10)
  - Tumarkin, Yigael, 1970, (3 folders) (Box 14, Folder 11-13)
  - Contemporary Greek Artists, undated, (6 folders) (Box 14, Folder 14-19)
  - Greek Artists, undated, (3 folders) (Box 14, Folder 20-22)
  - Merkin, Richard, undated, (2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 23-24)
  - Peire, Luc, undated, (3 folders) (Box 14, Folder 25-27)
  - Simeti, Turi, undated (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Vivancos, Miguel, undated, (2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 29-30)
  - Wragg, John, undated, (2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 31-32)
  - Nivola: Architectural Projects, 1963, (10 items; Oversized material from Box 11, F7) (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - 400 Years of Italian Art, 1967, (3 items; Oversized material from Box 13, F19) (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Millington-Drake, transparencies, 1969, (3 items; Oversized material from Box 14, F4) (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Printed Material, 1961-1970, Series 3:; (Box 15; 0.5 linear foot)
  This series contains various exhibition catalogs and invitations, as well as catalogs from Milan-based Galleria Dell'Ariete from 1961-1970.
  - Aldrich Museum of Contemporary Art, 1967-1969 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - De Sanctis, Fabio and Ugo Sterpini, 1963-1964 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Max Ernst, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Finch College Museum of Art, "Art in Process", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Galleria Dell'Ariete #75-79, #81-83, 1961-1962 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Galleria Dell'Ariete #84-86, #88-92, 1962-1963 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Galleria Dell'Ariete #93-94, #96-98, #102-107, 1963-1965 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Galleria Dell'Ariete #108-109, #111-114, #116, #118-119, 1965-1966 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Galleria Dell'Ariete #120-128, #130, #132, 1966-1967 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Galleria Dell'Ariete #133-138, #140-142, 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Galleria Dell'Ariete #143, #145-146, #148-151, #155-160, 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Goeritz, Mathias, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Hofstra Invitational Exhibition, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Invitations: Exhibits, 1965-1966 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Magritte, Rene, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Merkin, Richard, "Stuff that Dramas are made of", 1967 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Rhode Island Arts Festival, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Steinberg, Saul, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - "The Surrealists", 1969 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Van Leyden, Ernst, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 20)
- Invoices, 1963-1971, Series 4:; (Box 15; 0.5 linear foot)
  Found here are invoices for artwork sold by Byron Gallery from 1963-1971.
  Invoices were arranged by the gallery in alphabetical order by the artist's last name. Loose invoices are filed at the end of the series in chronological order.
  - Byron Gallery Invoices, Artists: B-M, 1966-1967 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Byron Gallery Invoices, Artists: N-O; A-C, 1963-1967 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Byron Gallery Invoices, Artists: C-N, 1963-1966 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Byron Gallery Invoices, Artists: P and Pre-Columbian, 1964-1971 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Byron Gallery Invoices, R-Y and other invoices, 1963-1966 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Byron Gallery Invoices, 1967 May-December (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Byron Gallery Invoices, 1968 January-April (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Byron Gallery Invoices, 1968 May-October (Box 15, Folder 28)
- Card Files, circa 1960s-1970s, Series 5:; (Box 16; 1 linear foot)
  This series contains index cards for artwork sold or returned by Byron Gallery.
  - Card Files of Works Sold or Returned, A-S, circa 1960s-1970s, (1 box) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Card Files of Works Sold or Returned (No Longer in Gallery), H-Z, circa 1960s-1970s, (1 box) (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Card Files of Works Sold or Returned, Pre-Columbian, circa 1960s-1970s, (1 box) (Box 16, Folder 3)